《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
菲什・穆尼还活着
Fish Mooney's alive.
你一直把我当白痴一样耍
You've been playing me for a chump.
不不不  不要
No! No. No. No! No!
你最好赶紧把机器停下
So, Duffy, you better stop this machine right now,
因为如果我死了
because if I die,
法尔科内阁下会派一队人马来
Don Falcone is gonna send a team up here
把你活活剥皮  再杀了你家人
to skin you alive and slaughter your family.
那个被从楼上扔下去的男人
That man who was thrown from the roof
凶手取走了他的肾上腺
the killer removed his adrenal glands.
总之  就是恐惧腺
Essentially, it's the fear gland.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
他还在逃
He's still out there.
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
翻译：灰灰是菇凉   夜影章鱼X   DustD
翻译：Silence   charcie   草草
时间轴：Kallen   艹明   最可爱的小胖子
特效&后期：饿得慌          校对&总监：草草
谁
Hello?
你是谁
Who are you?
不行了吗
How you doing?
起来  给我起来
Jump! Get up!
揍他
Slug 'er!
来啊
Come on!
不要
No, no.
No! No!
我在做梦吧
I'm dreaming, right?
真希望如此  女士
Oh, I hope so, lady.
真希望如此啊
I sure hope so.
该死的
Oh, hell.
这俩是怎么回事
What's up with them?
他们在等什么
What are they waiting for?
第一个对新来姑娘动手的人
First man that comes at a new girl
几乎总会被后来的人偷袭
nearly always gets jumped by the second man.
是吗
Is that right?
我向你们保证  小子们
Here's a promise, boys.
你们中第一个扑向我的  会立刻
The first of you to come at me will die like...
一命呜呼
that.
第二个会死得慢些
The second will die slow.
好了  小子们
So, boys...
谁想先来
...who's first?
谢谢  晚餐很美妙
Thank you. That was wonderful.
嗯  出租车
Yeah. Taxi!
而且没有案卷捣乱
And no case files.
我们一次也没提到工作
And we didn't mention work once.
-我们还不算无药可救  -嗯
- There's hope for us yet. - Yeah.
这...是我们第三次约会吗
So, what is this, our third date?
我想是的
I believe that's correct.
约会三次了  我还没去过你的公寓
Three dates, and I still haven't been to your apartment.
你对我公寓的哪个房间比较感兴趣
Well, what particular room in my apartment are you interested in?
-我也说不好  厨房怎么样  -很小
- Oh, I don't know. How's the kitchen? - Small.
-客厅呢  -太黑
- Living room? - Dark.
-那卧室如何  -我觉得你会喜欢卧室的
- What about the bedroom? - The bedroom I think you'd like.
是吗  出租车
Yeah? Taxi!
不过今天不行
But not tonight.
不行吗
No?
我得睡个好觉
I have to get a good night's sleep.
明早要开始新工作
I start a new job in the morning.
新工作  恭喜  你什么时候换的工作
A new job? Congratulations. Since when?
今早才确定下来的
I heard this morning.
我不想毁了晚餐  一直谈这事
I didn't want to spoil dinner with a whole big discussion about it.
这事怎么会毁了晚餐
Why would it spoil dinner?
我要来哥谭市警局工作了
I'm coming to work at the GCPD.
我是你们的新法医
I'm you're new medical examiner.
你开玩笑的吧
You're kidding.
太好了
That's great.
真的吗
Is it?
当然  就是我建议你来警局工作的
Of course. I mean, I was the one that suggested you work there.
对  可是现在成真了
Yes, but now it's real.
很好啊
So? Good.
好不好到时就知道了
We'll see, won't we?
晚安
Good night.
加图索・马克思  单身  63岁
Gennaro Marx, single, 63.
高中英语老师
High school English teacher.
他身上有跟上一个被害人完全相同的手术切口
Same exact surgical incisions as our last victim.
猜猜他没有肾上腺的几率有多大
What are the odds he's got no adrenal glands?
凶手拿肾上腺做什么
So, what's he doing with them?
为什么
Why?
你怎么回事  救我
What's the matter with you? Help me!
你为什么不来救我  杰拉尔德
Why won't you help me, Gerald?
救我
Help me...
哥谭
第一季  第十五集
东西都带齐了吗  布鲁斯少爷
Do you have everything you need, Master Bruce?
带齐了
Yes.
你愿意的话  我还是可以陪你去的
I can still come with you, if you want me to.
不
No.
那样不好
It wouldn't be right.
当然
No. Of course.
我没事的  阿尔弗雷德
I'll be fine, Alfred.
你不用担心
You don't have to worry.
谁说我担心了
Who said I was worried?
我天黑前就回来
I'll be back before dark.
我之前去走过这条路
I've been on this hike before, you know.
但都有你父亲陪
Not without your father.
过来
Come here.
他会赞同的
He would have approved, you know.
你这样延续传统
Carrying on the tradition like this.
我父亲和我会待一夜
My father and I stayed overnight.
我们会早起看日出
We woke up early to watch the sunrise.
这不一样
It's not the same.
那明年吧
Well, maybe next year, then.
去吧
Well, off you go then.
然后  最糟糕的是
And then, the worst of it...
马罗尼把我锁在一辆汽车里
Maroni had me locked me inside a sedan
想活活挤死我
and tried to crush me alive.
您也能想象我多么担心
So, well, you can imagine my concern.
马罗尼不是那种说放手就放手的人
Maroni's not a man to let things go,
我担心他会来报复我
and I fear he will come after me in retaliation.
你不打算把这里收拾一下吗
Were you planning to clean up the place?
什么
What?
当然  如果您希望的话
Oh, um, I... I can... if you like.
需要收拾一下
It needs it.
那是血迹吗
Is that blood?
大概吧
Perhaps.
但法尔科内阁下
But Don Falcone...
顺便
While you're at it...
也重新装潢一下
maybe you could do something about the design.
装潢
The design?
这里一股菲什・穆尼的气息
It reeks of Fish Mooney.
你觉得灯怎么样
What do you think about the lamps?
法尔科内阁下  您或许没听清
Don Falcone, maybe you didn't hear me.
我需要您的保护
I need your protection.
马罗尼一定会想杀我的
Maroni will surely try and kill me.
嗯
Yes.
灯得换掉
The lamps should go.
法尔科内阁下  求您
Don Falcone, please!
马罗尼想活剥了我  您却让我重装修
Maroni wants my scalp, and you'd have me redecorate.
这间夜店能挣大钱
This nightclub makes a lot of money.
没有钱  我们就没有势力
Without money, we lose influence.
没有势力  我们就失去控制权
Without influence, we lose control.
没有控制权  马罗尼一定会杀死你
And without control, Maroni killing you is no longer a hypothetical.
毫无疑问
It's a foregone conclusion.
所以我要重开这间夜店
That's why I want to reopen it.
你来打理
Under your care.
我可以拥有这间夜店吗
I can have the club?
这归我了
It's mine?
这是你应得的
You've earned it.
你再也不用偷偷摸摸  监视马罗尼了
Your days of sneaking around, spying on Maroni, are over.
你现在是我的人了
You're with me now.
光明正大
Publicly.
以后一切都不一样了
Things are gonna be much different.
好好收拾下这里  重新开张
So spruce up the place, get it open.
至于马罗尼  我来处理
As for Maroni, leave him to me.
那是什么
What do you got?
被害人教英语的学校的年鉴
Year book where the victim taught English.
告诉你
Tell you one thing--
我当年上高中时女生可没这么漂亮
girls didn't look like this when I was back in high school.
别激动
Easy...
就是说说
I'm just sayin'.
你好啊  吉姆
Hi, Jim.
小莱  你还记得哈维吧
Lee. You remember Harvey, right?
你好啊  小莱
Hi, Lee.
小莱是我们的新法医
Lee's our new M.E.
开玩笑吧
You're joking.
-没有  -太好了  你们见过了
- No. - Oh, good. You've met.
我和戈登警探已经认识了
Oh, Detective Gordon and I already know each other.
对了  在阿卡姆认识的吧
Oh, right. From Arkham?
嗯  阿卡姆
Right. Arkham.
欢迎加入
Welcome aboard.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们稍后再跟她说你们的案情
You can fill her in on your cases later.
汤普金斯医生  能跟我过来吗
Dr. Thompkins, will you follow me?
有很多东西需要你了解下
Lots to get you up to speed on.
很高兴再见到你  警探
It was good to see you again, Detective.
见到你也很高兴  医生
It was really good to see you, Doctor.
你运气真差啊  兄弟
You have no luck at all, do you, brother?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
找到个那么好的姑娘
You find a fine lady like that,
结果她来和你一起工作了
and she comes to work with you in the same building?
真是太可惜了
It's a damn shame.
为什么
Why?
办公室恋情总是以眼泪收场  眼泪
Office romance always ends in tears-- tears!
不会变成那样的
It's not gonna be like that.
相信我  我有体会
Trust me. I know.
杰拉尔德・克兰先生
生物学
就是他
There.
我的上帝姥姥
Holy Mother Mary.
-你找到了  -简直活灵活现
- You got him? - Staring right back at me.
就是他  就是他  泳池的那个人
That's him. That's him. That's the guy from the pool.
他叫杰拉尔德・克兰
His name is Gerald Crane.
是名生物学老师
He's a biology teacher.
学校还有几小时才放学
School doesn't let out for hours.
走吧
Let's go.
我是凯利
I'm Kelly.
菲什
Fish.
鱼[菲什]
Fish?
没错  就是菲什
That's what I said: Fish.
那么  我们在哪
So... where are we?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
有人觉得是监狱
Some people think it's a prison.
有人觉得是地狱
Some think it's Hell.
我大多数时候只是觉得冷
I just think it's cold, mostly.
早餐
Breakfast.
不
No.
得让老大先吃
You got to let the boss eat first.
大家叫他梅斯
People call him Mace.
他是管事的
He's the one in charge, hmm?
好了  好了
Okay. Okay.
杰拉尔德有天突然打电话说不来了
Gerald called in one day and said he wasn't coming in.
我再就没有他消息了
That's the last I heard of him.
让我猜猜  这是大概三周前的事
Let me guess, that was about three weeks ago?
-是啊  -邻居说他是那时搬的家
- Yeah. - That's when neighbors said he up and moved out.
警员搜查过了  什么都没有
Unis searched the place. Nothing.
关于克兰你能告诉我们些什么
So what can you tell us about Crane?
他是个好老师
He was a good teacher.
很专注  还是位好父亲
Focused. And a good father.
他很关心他儿子  乔纳森
He was very protective of his son Jonathan.
但是他也很安静  阴郁
But he could be quiet, too. Somber.
应该和他妻子有关
Think it had to do with his wife--
她六七年前死掉了
she died six or seven years ago.
她怎么死的
She died? How?
车祸
Car accident.
克兰有没有谈过恐惧或是恐惧症
Did Crane ever talk about fear or phobias?
怎么了
Why?
有人针对恐惧症患者吗
Is someone targeting phobics?
是的
Yeah.
杀害他们吗
Killing them?
你能想到什么吗
Does this mean something to you?
那些被害人
These victims,
他们有没有丢失肾上腺
were they missing their adrenal glands?
你怎么知道的
How'd you know that?
这是一篇杰拉尔德
This was an academic paper
几个月前写的学术论文
that Gerald wrote a few months ago.
他拜托我帮他校对
He asked me to proof it for him.
杰拉尔德有个理论
See, Gerald had a theory
说恐惧是人类进化中的瑕疵
that fear was an evolutionary flaw in humans.
战争  强奸  偷窃  谋杀
War, rape, theft, murder--
都因恐惧而起
it was all caused by fear.
他十分沉迷于其中
He was obsessed with it.
那么克兰杀了那些人
So Crane killed these people
并取走肾上腺是为了测试一个理论
and took their glands to test a theory?
不  杰拉尔德并不想证明他对恐惧的观点是对的
No... Gerald wasn't trying to prove he was right about fear.
他想要治愈自己的恐惧
He was trying to cure himself of it.
克兰治愈恐惧的方法是
Crane's idea of curing fear
自己进行预防注射
was to inoculate himself against it.
-就像治疗疾病那样  -没错
- Like a disease? - Exactly.
但是为了这么做
But in order to do so,
他得收集到引发恐惧的浓缩激素
he needed a condensed source of the hormones that cause fear.
恐惧症患者
Phobics.
克兰掠夺人的恐惧吗
Crane's preying on them?
以恐吓来强化人的恐惧
Spiking their fear by scaring them
然后为了提取激素而杀了他们
and then killing them in order to harvest the hormones?
见鬼
Damn!
这种东西他需要多少
How much of this stuff does he need?
什么意思
What do you mean?
他还要杀多少人
How many more people is he gonna kill?
当然  问得好
Oh. Of course. Good question.
我想这要取决于他的害怕程度吧
Depends on how scared he is, I guess.
他害怕什么
What's he scared of?
在斯科蒂的恐惧互助组里
In Scottie's phobia support group,
他说他害怕失败
he said he was afraid of failure.
谁不害怕失败  肯定还有别的恐惧
Who isn't? It's gotta be something else.
-你听说了吗  -听说什么
- Did you hear? - Hear what?
我们这儿来了一位新法医
That we got a new medical examiner.
比上一任好太多了
Much better than the old one.
而且她很香
And she smells nice.
看到没  吉姆  这就有情敌了
See, Jim? Competition already.
看看这个
Look at this.
克兰准备了两例接种规程
Crane developed protocols for two inoculations,
他自己和另一个人  对象B
himself and somebody else-- Subject B.
不知道那是谁
I wonder who that is.
爸爸
Dad...
Dad?
你没事吧
You okay?
我好极了
I'm glorious.
成功了  乔纳森
It's working, Jonathan.
我说过会成功的
I said it would.
就要轮到你了
And it's almost your turn.
你将会永远摆脱恐惧
You will be free of fear forever.
我会把你治好的
You'll be cured.
准备好了吗  乔纳森
Are you ready, Jonathan?
准备好了吗  儿子
Are you ready, son?
-谢谢你邀我来  -这是我的荣幸
- Thank you for having me. - My pleasure.
我们是朋友吧
We're friends, right?
-当然是  -那我就不说客套话了
- Of course. - Then let me talk to you as a friend.
你想一起吃午餐  一起走走
You want to have lunch, take a walk,
我很乐意
I'm happy to.
但光凭三明治和散步是无法阻止我杀企鹅的
But a sandwich and a stroll ain't gonna keep me from killing Penguin.
那个卑鄙小人死定了
That little rat is dead.
那好吧
So be it.
科波特先生  这样行吗
Mr. Cobblepot, will this do?
我们不上这酒
We will not be serving that.
不不不
No, no, no.
我让你们丢掉帘子  不是再挂回去
I said lose the drapes, not tie them back!
还有十个小时就开张了
We're opening in ten hours!
-抱歉  -老大
- Sorry. - Hey, boss...
做好了
They're ready.
奥斯瓦尔德夜店
刚打出来的
Still warm from the printer.
今晚不能有差错  盖布
Nothing can go wrong tonight, Gabe.
今晚不止是开幕仪式
This is more than an opening.
更是我的重要时刻
It's my moment.
请帖印得非常好
They're perfect.
把请帖送去给名单上的每一个人
Take these to everybody on the list.
除了这张
But not this one.
这张我要亲自去送
This one I want to deliver in person.
我只想说句话
I just want a word.
我没有恶意
I mean no harm.
别再往前走了
That's close enough.
没有恶意吗
No harm, huh?
你是这里的老大吗
So, you're the boss in here?
是的
I am.
为什么是你
Why you?
这里有不少大块头啊
I see a lot of tough guys around here.
这是这里唯一一把刀
This is the only blade in the place.
就在我手里
And I'm holding it.
好吧
Fair enough.
我想跟你做个交易
I want to make a deal with you.
-交易  -是的
- A deal? - Yeah.
我有些本领  兴许你用得到
I think I might have skills that could be useful to you.
是吗
Really?
什么本领
What skills, exactly?
各种各样
All kinds.
你保护我不受这些禽兽伤害  我就让你见识一下
You protect me from these animals, and I'll show you.
你觉得你值得保护吗
You think you're worth protecting?
绝对值得
You have no idea.
有什么能帮你的吗
Can I help you?
不见得  你能吗
I don't think so. Can you?
你要怎么样
What do you want?
我想要  穷人有的  富人要的
What I want, the poor have, the rich need,
如果你吃了它  会翘辫子的东西
and if you eat it you'll die.
这是...
Is this...
你这是让我猜谜语吗
Are you asking me a riddle?
-你喜欢谜语吗  -不喜欢
- Do you like riddles? - No.
那你要放弃吗
So do you give up?
-朋友...  -虚无
- Friend, lookit... - Nothing.
答案是"虚无"  穷人有  富人要
The answer is nothing. The poor have it, the rich need it,
-如果你吃了它  -你是谁
- and if you eat it... - Who are you?
爱德华
Edward.
尼格玛
Nygma.
我知道你是谁哦
I know who you are.
那你就该知道你站得太近了
Then you know that you're standing too close.
你知道吗  雄性帝企鹅为了给蛋保暖
Did you know that male emperor penguins keep their eggs warm
会把蛋放在脚上
by balancing them on their feet?
厉害吧
Isn't that neat?
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you, sir.
走你的路
Keep moving.
没问题
Will do.
通话记录吗
Cell phone records?
还有信用卡结算单
And credit card statements.
-帮把手  -好的
- Give me a hand. - Yeah, sure.
稍等一下
Uh, give me a minute.
慢慢来
Take your time.
很高兴见到你  老朋友
It's good to see you, old friend.
你来这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
我想邀请你来我办的派对
I wanted to invite you to a party I'm hosting.
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
明白了
I hear you.
太忙了  是吧
Too busy, I suppose.
案子很棘手吗
Are you on a tricky case?
需要我帮忙吗
Anything I can help you with?
上次合作多愉快
It worked so well the last time.
我不需要你帮忙
I don't want your help.
上次就不该求你办事
It was a mistake to ask.
我不希望你来这里
I don't want you coming here.
你不该这样对我  吉姆
You shouldn't treat me this way, Jim.
很快  你就会需要我帮忙了
One day soon, you'll need my help.
你会来找我的
You'll come to me.
与朋友在黑暗中同行
And walking with a friend in the dark
总好过一个人在光明里独行
is better than walking alone in the light.
祝你好运  早日结案
Good luck with your police work.
还有
And...
拜托
please...
再考虑考虑我的邀请
Reconsider my invitation.
没有你  感觉不对劲
It won't be the same without you.
你信任我吗
Do you trust me?
当然
Of course.
我爱你  儿子
I love you, son.
我绝不会做伤害你的事
I wouldn't do anything to harm you.
打吧  赶紧
Just go. Go ahead.
你真是个好孩子
You're being a very good boy.
别挣扎
Yes, don't struggle.
看着我  看着我的眼睛
Look at me, look in my eyes.
布・韦   托・韦
-好啊  -你也好啊
- Hey. - Hey, yourself.
第一天上班感觉如何
How's your first day going?
-忙死了  -很好
- Busy. - Good.
那好  我得回去忙了
Good, well, I got to get back, so...
等下
Yeah.
小莱
Lee.
在这里我们这样不好
We can't do that here.
为什么  你上次还当着全警局的面亲我呢
Why? Last time, you kissed me in the middle of the bullpen.
你当时可不在这儿上班
You weren't working here then.
-有什么区别吗  -这样不专业
- That makes a difference to you? - It's not professional.
希望不会啊
Well, I should hope not.
小莱
Lee...
你好啊  布洛克
Hey, Bullock.
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to interrupt.
什么事
What's up?
没你的感情生活要紧
Nothing that can't wait on your love life.
一点公事而已
Just business.
抽根雪茄怎么样
How does a cigar sound?
我存了些上等的古巴雪茄  一直想抽呢
I've got some beautiful Castros I've been waiting to try.
卡麦  别兜圈子了
Carmine, talk straight with me.
你到底想怎样
Why are you doing this?
确实  企鹅挣钱有两下子
Granted, Penguin is a money-maker.
但你为什么这么花心思想留他一命
How come you're laying all this grease on me to keep him alive?
你有何用意
What's your angle?
他很聪明  我喜欢手下有这种
He's clever. And I like to have a clever man beside me
知道自己分量的聪明人  这你懂的
who knows his place in life. You know how that goes.
是啊  完全懂
Yeah. All day.
他也够聪明
He's clever enough to know
知道他这样的小怪物
that a freakish little man like him
是当不了老大的
is never going to be the boss.
有道理
True enough.
难不成你给我几根雪茄
So I'm supposed to give you a prime asset like that,
我就把这么个人才让给你
and you're gonna bring out some nice old cigars?
我给你的开价当然要可观得多
Of course I'll show my gratitude to you in a more formal way.
这不是钱的问题
This is not a money thing.
这是个人恩怨
This is personal.
我理解
I understand.
你知道斯坦利・特布尔首席法官吗
Do you know Chief Judge Stanley Turnbull?
当然知道
Of course.
他是法院里最他妈难对付的混蛋
He's the meanest son of a mother bitch in the courthouse.
不错
Yes.
强硬又正直的人
A hard and righteous man.
也很有影响力
Powerful, too.
还抓了我好几个哥们
Put down some good friends of mine.
你把他的狗头拿来给我
You bring me his ugly head
再加20万
and, say, 200 grand,
咱们就成交
and you got a deal.
我给你的可比他的狗头强多了
Oh, I'll give you a better deal than his head.
我的老天
On my mother's life.
特布尔法官
Judge Turnbull.
他跟一个小情郎出去鬼混
He was out with a young man.
我把他药倒了抓来了这里
I had him drugged and brought here.
现在他是你的人了
Now he's all yours.
我的
Mine?
当然  我也用得着他
I mean, we'll share him...
不过  说起来
of course, but, uh, in spirit,
他是你的人了
he's yours.
朝镜头笑笑
Now smile for the camera.
太棒了
It's beautiful.
我们肯定疏忽了什么
We must be missing something.
那你哥们企鹅呢
What about your pal Penguin?
他怎么了
What about him?
他帮我们办了弗拉斯的案子
He helped us with Flass.
没准这案子也能帮上忙
Maybe he'll help us with Crane.
不  我不会回去找他的
No. I'm not going back to him.
-值得一试  -不值得
- It's worth a try. - No, it's not.
那我们就只能干等着再死人了
Then we wait for another body to drop,
因为光在这儿坐着可抓不到他
because we're not gonna find him here.
你说的对
Yeah, you're right.
我们追随克兰是抓不到他的
We're never gonna be able to track Crane.
我们得赶在他前面
We gotta get ahead of him
弄清楚他的动机
by finding out what's driving him.
我们知道他的动机
We know what's driving him.
-他对恐惧的痴迷  -是啊
- He's obsessed with fear. - Yeah.
但为什么
But why?
他怕什么
What's he afraid of?
他遭遇了什么事  才变成这样
What happened to him that made him this way?
他妻子因车祸丧生
His wife was killed in a car crash.
嗯
Yeah.
查查这个
Check that out.
查到了  凯伦・克兰
Got it. Karen Crane.
嗯
Yeah.
这里显示她死于家里着火  而非车祸
Says here she died in a house fire, not a car accident.
你觉得那个同事是撒谎了吗
You think the coworker was lying?
另有三个人给出了相同的说法
Three other people said the same thing.
克兰一定是因为什么原因而撒谎了
Crane must've lied about it for some reason.
大火时发生了什么
What happened in the fire?
文章说着火的时候
Article says she was sleeping upstairs
她在楼上睡觉
when the fire broke out.
丈夫杰拉尔德和儿子  8岁的乔纳森
Husband Gerald and son Jonathan, eight,
都在楼下
were downstairs.
克兰妻子死的时候他也在家
Crane was in the house when his wife died?
却没去救她  怪不得他要撒谎
And didn't save her. No wonder he lied.
他觉得羞愧
He's ashamed.
他因为恐惧  而眼看妻子死去
His fear is the reason his wife died.
所以他才这么做
That's why he's doing this.
克兰家的老地址  走吧
Address for the old Crane house. Let's go.
深夜起火
女子殒命
好
Okay.
乔纳森
Jonathan!
别跑了  小乔  别跑了
Stop, Johnny, stop!
站住
Stop there!
我们已经开始了
We've started the protocol.
就一定要做完  否则对你没好处的
It must be completed, it will be harmful for you otherwise.
我...不能再做一次了
I can't... I can't do it again.
想想啊  小乔  再也不用害怕了
Think of it Johnny-- no more fear.
我都不像你那样害怕
I'm not-I'm not even afraid like you.
我们都害怕
We're all afraid.
这世上的每个男人和女人
Every man and woman on the planet.
我们都站在深渊边缘
We're all standing at the edge of the abyss,
吓得无法动弹
paralyzed by fear.
来吧  儿子
Now, come on, son.
相信我
Trust me.
我只是想帮你
I just want to help you.
帮助全人类
And mankind.
全人类啊  小乔
Mankind, Johnny.
你得勇敢点  好吗
Now you must be brave, hmm?
来吧  儿子
Come on, son.
你愿意跟我一起完成吗
Are you with me?
那我们回家吧
Then let's go back to the house.
很快就能结束了  我保证
It'll all be over before you know it, I promise.
走吧
Come on.
加把劲
Ah, come on.
加把劲啊
Come on.
什么事  博士
What's up, Doc?
我叫梅斯
The name's Mace.
真好听  但我喜欢给朋友起外号
That's cute, but I like to give my friends nicknames.
你就叫博士吧
And yours is Doc...
因为你块头虽大  眼睛里却充满智慧
'cause you have such a wise look in your eyes for such a big man.
脾气真像爆竹啊
A real little firecracker, huh?
爆竹只炸一次
A firecracker goes off once
然后就没用了
and then just lies there.
我是国庆节的烟火
What you're looking at is the Fourth of July.
坐过来
Come sit by me.
-那么我们交易成了  -当然  宝贝儿
- Does that mean we have a deal? - Sure, baby.
我还有几件事想跟你商量
Well, I have a couple of riders I would like to talk to you...
别说了  宝贝儿
Hush, now, baby.
你话太多  要惹我不开心了
You talk too much and you'll make me mad.
我想想
Huh, let's see...
第一件事
That's rider number one.
就是别叫我"宝贝儿"
Don't call me "Baby."
我叫菲什・穆尼
My name is Fish Mooney.
我现在是老大了
I'm in charge now.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
-不  不  -爸爸
- No, no, no! - Dad.
走吧  我们得马上走了
Come on, we have to go now.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
爸爸  他们一进来就会逮捕你的
Dad, they are going to arrest you once they come in here.
我们得赶快走了
We have to go now!
还有时间  我们可以完成的
There's still time. We can complete the protocol.
我们进来了
Coming in.
你干什么
What are you doing?
我们得完成
We have to finish the protocol.
-必须这样  -爸爸  那太多了
- It's the only way. - Dad, that's too much.
必须如此
It's the only way.
听我说  爸爸
Look, Dad...
时间不够了
there's not enough time.
没事的
It'll be fine.
-我爱你  儿子  -别
- I love you, son. - Stop!
手举起来
Hands where we can see 'em!
手举起来  否则我们开枪了
Hands in the air or we'll shoot!
你以为我怕你们吗
You think I'm afraid of you?
-别再往前走了  -怕你们的枪吗
- Not another step! - Afraid of your guns?
我无所畏惧
I have no fear!
抓他  我去看孩子
You take him. I'll get the kid.
叫救护车
Call an ambulance.
Call an ambulance!
没事了  孩子
It's all right, son!
没事了
It's all right!
你好啊  布鲁斯少爷
Hello, there, Master Bruce.
你好慢啊
Well, you certainly took your time.
出来的路上去吃饭喝酒了吗
What, did you stop off for a pie and a pint on the way out, did you?
你在这儿多久了
How long have you been there?
不好说...一小时了吧
Well, I don't know, about... about an hour.
你开始爬山的时候就来了
Just when you started climbing up that very nasty hill.
多谢帮忙了
Thanks for your help.
又不是我害你掉下去的
Yeah, I never got you down there, you know.
你没事吧
You all right?
过来
Come here.
我好冷
I'm cold,
好累  还扭伤了脚踝
I'm tired, and my ankle's sprained.
我想回家
I just want to go home.
你想回家
You want to go home?
还是想等等  看日出
Or do you want to wait and watch the sunrise?
就像跟你爸爸一起那样
Like you did with your dad.
阿尔弗雷德
Well, Alfred...
如果你没问题  我们就留下吧
...we can only stay if you think you can handle it.
如果我没问题
If I can handle it?
伙计  这地方跟我待过的
Mate, this place is positively cushy
一些地方相比简直是天堂了
compared to some of the places I've slept at.
喝茶吗  小猴子
Cup of tea, you cheeky monkey?
企鹅
Penguin.
你去哪
Where you going?
马罗尼阁下
Don Maroni.
见到您真是荣幸
It's such a pleasure to see you.
瞧瞧你
Look at you.
之前还在我车的后备箱里  这就有自己的夜店了
From the trunk of my car to running your own club.
这地方不错  企鹅
The place looks good, Penguin.
人不少啊
Hell of a turnout.
-是啊  -要坐吗
- Yeah. - How 'bout a table?
喝点东西
Drinks?
我请
My compliments, of course.
挺贵的啊
Expensive stuff.
我瞧瞧
Let me see.
我跟法尔科内谈了谈
I had a little chat with Falcone.
我来是想告诉你我们之间没事了
I came here to let you know that all is kosher between us.
只要你不再把我的秘密抖露给法尔科内
Long as you don't go giving Falcone any more of my secrets.
当然
No.
不会的
Nothing like that.
当然
Of course not.
拿个杯子吧
Grab a glass.
你最好祈祷那老头子法尔科内长命百岁
You better hope that old man, Falcone, lives a long life.
因为他一死
'Cause the second he's out the picture,
你也得上西天
so are you.
小布少爷
Master B.
日出了
Sunrise.
你还好吗
How are you?
我听说你的疑犯死了
I heard your suspect was killed.
他拿枪对着我和哈维
Came after Harvey and me with a gun.
-没办法  -我很遗憾
- Didn't have a choice. - I'm so sorry.
他儿子呢
What about his son?
医务人员稳定了他的情况
Paramedics were able to stabilize him.
我这就去医院看望他
I'm heading over to the hospital now, to check in on him.
有消息告诉我
Well, let me know how he is.
嗯
I will.
安顿下来了
So, settled in here, huh?
差不多了吧
Uh, almost.
你觉得会喜欢这里吗
Think you're gonna like it here?
目前还喜欢
I do. So far.
很好
Good.
我有马戏团的门票
Um, I have tickets to the circus.
要一起来吗
Do you want to come with me?
-马戏团  -是啊  他们不错呢
- The circus? - Yeah. They're good.
没有什么可怜的大象
No, uh, sad elephants.
马戏团  好啊
The circus. Sure. Why not?
小莱
Look, Lee...
在警局不能接吻
no kissing, here, on the job.
好吗  我认真的
Okay? I'm serious.
好
Okay.
真的吗
Okay?
如果你这么在意你的硬汉形象的话
If your hard-ass reputation is worth that much to you.
-这是工作场合  -警察也有感情啊
- This is a place of work. - Cops have feelings, too.
显露感情没什么不专业的
It's not unprofessional to show your feelings.
是不专业  这种感情就不专业
Yeah, it is. Those kinds of feelings, yeah.
那好吧
Fine. Be that way.
开玩笑呢
I'm just joking.
我会小心的
I'll be discreet.
好了  大家都凑过来
All right, everyone gather round!
之前这里毫无秩序
Up until now, there's been no order in here.
毫无...规矩
No... structure.
以后要改改了
Things are gonna change.
她回来了
She's back.
我的眼睛
My eyes.
他们挖了我的眼睛
They took my eyes.
那孩子被注入了高剂量的浓缩激素
The boy received a massive dose of condensed hormones--
皮质醇  肾上腺素
cortisol, adrenaline--
还有一种我们尚未查清的混合物
and another compound we're still trying to identify.
这种组合药剂险些要了他的命
The combination nearly killed him.
但他会没事吗
But he's gonna live?
是的
Yes.
但我们给他做了断层扫描
But we ran a CAT scan
以检查他是否遭遇了脑损伤
in order to determine if he suffered any brain damage.
检查结果
The results...
我们前所未见
we've never seen anything like them before.
激素本身早已排出
The hormones themselves have long since worn off,
但其效力
but the effects,
似乎还存在
they seem to be lingering.
什么意思
What are you saying?
他还处于恐惧中
That he's still in fear?
不仅是恐惧
Well, not just fear.
乔纳森的脑活动显示
Jonathan's brain activity shows
他一直处于极度恐惧之中
he's in a constant state of intense terror.
这要多久会消退
How long until this goes away?
这个...
Well...
问题就在这里  警探
that's just the thing, Detective.
我们不确定它会消退
We can't be certain it ever will.
想象你最怕的东西
Imagine the thing you fear most in the world.
想象你满眼都是那个
Imagine that it's all you see.
每时每刻
Every waking hour.
不不  不要
No, no, no!
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com